JOSEPH SENYONGA

Ottawa, ON K1T2Y9 613-884-2444 Joseph.Senyonga@hotmail.com LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Ambitious, career-focused job seeker with 6+ years proven experience in written and verbal communication, analytical thinking and problem solving, and team collaboration with a certificate in Full Stack development from Carleton University, eager to obtain an entry-level Full Stack Developer position to help launch career while achieving company goals.

SKILLS

- Analytical Thinking and Problem Solving
- REST API Design and Development
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Responsive Design
- MERN: MongoDB, ExpressJS, React, NodeJS
- Databases: Mongoose, MySQL, Sequelize, GraphQL, Apollo GraphQL
- Source and Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Software Testing and Validation

PROJECTS

Capstone

A daily workout tracker to help you maintain your physical health by adding workouts to your calendar and tracking your progress over the months.

• Source code | Live Link

Technologies Used

• MongoDB | ExpressJS | React | NodeJS | ChakraUI | Prettier | GraphQL | Apollo GraphQL | Mongoose

Git Social

A social app for new developers to post about their projects and solicit help from other developers looking to build their portfolios.

• Source code | Live Link

Technologies Used

• NodeJS | Handlebars | Sequelize | MySQL | Materialize | GitHub | JSdocs | Radix Icons

EXPERIENCE -

THE IAN MARTIN GROUP

Ottawa, ON

Team Coordinator 12/2020 to Current

- Developed leadership abilities while overseeing a 10-person team that I met with daily to discuss roadblocks, promote problem-solving and teamwork and communicate responsibilities to each group member to delegate tasks.
- Successfully collaborated with management team to meet organizational and departmental goals.
- Employed communication skills to convey issues, risks and concerns to management and offered solutions and mitigation strategies.
- Delivered high-quality service by responding quickly to client issues and addressing challenging concerns successfully.
- Collaborated with team to complete hundreds of successful case investigations in 2021-2022 during the omicron surge in a demanding environment while adhering to rapidly evolving Ministry of Health Guidance.
- Arranged and oversaw adequate and suitable training for case managers on how to conduct COVID-19 public health investigations.
- Oversaw 10-person team, discussed project roadblocks to promote issue resolution and used best practices.

CARLETON UNIVERSITY CODING BOOTCAMP

Ottawa, ON

Full Stack Web Developer

05/2022 to 11/2022

- Managed both back-end and front-end aspects of development process.
- Modified existing software systems to enhance performance and add new features.
- Interpreted mock-ups to create high-quality coding that functions according to specifications.

- Assisted other developers with coding, troubleshooting, and debugging.
- Built professional relationships with team and clients to help speed communication and attain project results.
- Reviewed information and elements regularly on websites and pages for accuracy and functionality.
- Defined and conducted design processes at all stages, including research, conceptualization, testing and implementation.
- Troubleshot, tested and remedied issues before software deployment.
- Reviewed project specifications and devised solutions for use across multiple websites.
- Implemented improvements to boost site performance.
- Maintained strong education in latest technologies, software, and hardware products for use in various projects.
- Redesigned sites to enhance navigation and improve visual appeal.
- Validated code for proper structuring, security and compatibility with different browsers, devices, or operating systems.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

CERTIFICATE: FULL STACK DEVELOPER

10/2022

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

DIPLOMA: REGISTERED PRACTICAL NURSE

12/2015

Centennial College of Applied Arts And Technology, Scarborough, ON